<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<qmrf_help name="QMRF Repository user guide">

<chapter anchor="background" name="Background" level="1">
<help>TODO</help>
</chapter>

<chapter anchor="ui" name="User interface" level="1">
<help>TODO</help>

<chapter anchor="guest" name="Guest actions" level="2">
		<help>
		The anonymous user is granted access to all published documents and can perform searching through simple or advanced options.
		</help>
		<chapter anchor="home" name="Home">
		<help>TODO</help>

		</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="search_documents" name="How to search for QMRF documents?">
		<help>
			Enter QMRF No. or some text in the relevant fields. Select Endpoint, Algorithm, Software or Authors from the list box.
			Check the fields which you would like to include in the query.
			Select "And" or "Or" from the drop down box at the left of the Search button, in order to specify how to combine the selected criteria.
			Press the Search button.
		</help>
		<help>
			Please note that searching is performed only within Published documents. In particular, Draft documents will not be visible through this search.
		</help>
		<help>
			Please note that the Endpoint list box contains predefined endpoint names. Some of the endpoints might not have associated QMRF documents.
		</help>
		</chapter>


		<chapter anchor="search_structures" name="How to search for chemical structures">
		<help>
			Select "Exact structure" or "Similarity". In case of "Similarity", please specify a threshold for the Tanimoto distance.
		</help>
		<help>
			Draw a compound in the Structure Diagram Editor on the right, or specify CAS RN., Formula, Chemical name or SMILES.
		</help>
			<help>
			All fields are combined by "AND".
		</help>
			<help>
			The structures in the QMRF Inventory are imported from attachments of type "training set" or "validation set", uploaded by the Authors.
			When a document is published, the chemical structures are imported in the QMRF Inventory and are linked to the corresponding document.
		</help>
			<help>
			The search returns a list of structures along with links to the corresponding QMRF documents.
			</help>
		</chapter>
</chapter>
<chapter anchor="user" name="User actions" level="2">
			<chapter anchor="register" name = "Register">
			<help>TODO</help>
			</chapter>
			<chapter anchor="login" name = "Log in">
			<help>TODO</help>
			</chapter>
			<chapter anchor="documents" name = "My documents">
			<help>TODO</help>
			</chapter>
			<chapter anchor="new_document" name = "Create new document">
			<help>TODO</help>
			</chapter>
</chapter>
<chapter anchor="admin" name="Administrative actions" level="2">
			<chapter anchor="register" name = "Register">
			<help>TODO</help>
			</chapter>
			<chapter anchor="login" name = "Log in">
					<help>TODO</help>
			</chapter>
			<chapter anchor="pending" name = "Pending QMRF documents">
		<help>
			A list of documents that await your action.
		</help>
			<help>
				For example a draft document will appear in Author's pending documents list until it is submitted to the QMRF Inventory.
				A document under revision will appear in Reviewer's pending documents list until it is published or returned to the Author.
		</help>
			</chapter>

		<chapter anchor="review" name="Review document">
		<help>
				Enter keywords and/or comments. Click the Update button.
		</help>
		</chapter>

		<chapter anchor="download" name="Download QMRF Document">
		<help>
				Allows downloading QMRF documents in different formats. Please note that XML is the native format for QMRF documents. QMRF documents in XML format can be opened and edited through the QMRF Editor.
				HTML, PDF and XLS formats are useful for archiving and printing purposes.
		</help>
	</chapter>

		<chapter anchor="actions" name="Actions available on QMRF Documents">
		<help>
				A set of links, allowing to perform different actions, according to the document status and user roles. For example
				an Author can edit a document and a Reviewer can review a document.
		</help>
	</chapter>

		<chapter anchor="version" name="QMRF document version">
		<help>
				Version is a number, used to track the different versions of a document. When a document is created, it has version "1" assigned.
				When the document is returned for a revision, the version is incremented by 1.
		</help>
	</chapter>

		<chapter anchor="user_name" name="QMRF document Author">
		<help>
				The QMRF Inventory user name of the document Author.
		</help>
	</chapter>

		<chapter anchor="email" name="E-mail of a QMRF user">
		<help>
A valid e-mail is required in order to register in QMRF Repository. The QMRF Inventory will send various notifications to the user email.
		</help>
	</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="lastdate" name="QMRF document date">
		<help>
				The timestamp of the last update of the document.
		</help>
	</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="qmrf_title" name="QMRF document title">
		<help>
The first 128 characters of the QMRF document title (Section 1.1)
		</help>
	</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="qmrf_number" name="QMRF Number">
		<help>
				The QMRF number is a unique identifier, assigned to a published QMRF document, in the form of Q A-B-C-D.
				The following fields will be used to assign a unique identifier:
		</help>
		<help>
		A: 4.2. Explicit algorithm
		</help>
		<help>
		B: 2.5. Model developer(s) and contact details
</help>
		<help>
		C: 1.3. Software coding the model
</help>
		<help>
		D: Version
</help>
		<help>
If data is not present in these fields the document will not be published.
</help>
		</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="publish" name="Publish new document">
				<help>
				Clicking the Publish button will assign a QMRF number of the form A-B-C-D, where A,B,C and D are defined below, and publish the QMRF document.
				</help>
				<help>
				Click "Retrieve number from catalog" to obtain the 
				corresponding numbers.
				If some of the fields are empty, return the document to the author to insert the missing data.
				</help>
		</chapter>

		<chapter anchor="user_keywords" name="Reviewer keywords">
				<help>
				Fill in the "Keywords" field if you would like to become a QMRF Inventory Reviewer.
				</help>
				<help>
				These keywords will be used by the QMRF Inventory Editor when assigning reviewers for QMRF documents. The editor will seek a match between the QMRF document keywords and the available Reviewers' keywords.
				</help>

		</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="verify_author" name="Verify if an user is a member of the QMRF and model authors list.">
				<help>
Verifies if an author with a matching e-mail address exists in the QMRF documents and models authors list. If not, provides a form to add a new author to the list.
				</help>
				<help>
The author names are usually appended when publishing documents in the QMRF Inventory.
				</help>
				<help>
The author list will be available as a lookup for relevant fields within the QMRF editor.
				</help>
		</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="roles" name="What are user roles and how to change/update roles.">
				<help>
				There are four role types: Author, Reviewer, Editor and Administrator, which can be assigned to the registered users.
				</help>
				<help>
				The Author can create and submit QMRF documents. Once submitted, the documents are reviewed by a Reviewer.
				The Reviewer can publish the document, or return it to the Author, if there is insufficient/unclear information.
				</help>
				<help>
				The Editor assigns Reviewers to the newly submitted documents.
				</help>
				<help>
				Upon registration, a new user is assigned only the Author role. The Reviewer role can be assigned to any user, but assignment can be done only by the Administrator.
				This can be done via the User profiles tab.
				</help>
				<help>
				Note: The Author role can not be withdrawn while there are documents under preparation (e.g. "Draft", "Under revision", "Submitted", "Returned for revision") for the respective Author.
				</help>
		</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="review_forbidden" name="Reviewing not allowed">
				<help>
				Document reviewing when the Reviewer and the Author share the same QMRF Inventory user name is not allowed.
				</help>
		</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="status" name="Document status">
				<help>
				A QMRF document can be in one of the following states: "Draft", "Under revision", "Submitted", "Returned for revision", "Archived", "Published".
				</help>
				<help>
				Draft: The document has "Draft" status, when just created by an Author, or when edited by an Author, after being returned for a revision. The document is visible only to the Author and the Administrator.
				</help>
				<help>
				Submitted: This status is assigned after the Author submits the document in the QMRF Inventory through the Final Submission page. The document is visible to the Author, the Editor and the Administrator. The Editor assigns the document to a Reviewer and the document becomes visible to the assigned Reviewer.
				</help>
				<help>
				Under revision: This status is set when the Reviewer is assigned a document to review. The document is visible only to the Author, the assigned Reviewer, the Editor and the Administrator.
				</help>
				<help>
				Returned for revision: This status is assigned if the assigned Reviewer considers the information in the document insufficient and returns the document to the Author. The document is visible only to the Author, the assigned Reviewer, the Editor and the Administrator.
				</help>
				<help>
				Archived: Upon returning for a revision, the original document is assigned "Archived" status, while a copy of the document is assigned "Returned for revision" status and is returned to the Author. Both documents are visible only to the Author, the assigned Reviewer, the Editor and the Administrator.
				</help>
				<help>
				Published: The document is assigned Published status when approved by the Reviewer. A unique QMRF number is assigned to the document. Published documents are visible to everybody, not only to registered users.
				</help>
		</chapter>
		
</chapter>
		<chapter anchor="registration_status" name="User registration status">
				<help>
				The registration status of a QMRF Inventory user can be one of the following: "Commenced", "Verified", "Confirmed", "Deleted". The registration status is visible only to the Administrator.
				</help>
				<help>
				Commenced: The registration status is "Commenced", upon a registration attempt from an user. At this stage, an email , containing a confirmation URL is sent to the user, in order to validate the email entered. 
				The user is expected to respond by clicking on the provided URL. 
				</help>
				<help>
				Verified: This status is assigned after the User had to responded to the validation email, by clicking on the URL provided. The user is NOT yet allowed to log in into the QMRF Inventory, for this purpose, an Administrator approval is necessary (see 'Confirmed' status).
				</help>
				<help>
				Confirmed: This status is set when the Administrator approves the User registration. Upon approval, an email is sent to the user, notifying his registration is confirmed and he can log in into the QMRF inventory.
				</help>
				<help>
				Deleted: This status is assigned if user is removed from the system.
				</help>
		</chapter>

</chapter>
</qmrf_help>